Drawn by a landscape as white as snow,
真っ白な景色にいま誘われて
Masshiro na keshiki ni ima sasowarete
I'm headed toward an unseen world.
僕は行くよ　まだ見ぬ世界へ
Boku wa yuku yo mada minu sekai e
I've been traveling while lost
迷子のまま旅していた
Maigo no mama tabi shiteita
Under this gray sky.
鼠色の空の下
Nezumiiro no sora no shita
Every day with new maps, stained with my many dreams.
日替わりの地図 いくつもの夢が滲んでいた
Higawari no chizu ikutsumo no yume ga nijindeita
I wonder if someday,
いつかはさ
Itsuka wa sa
Even with these tiny steps of mine,
ちっぽけな僕のこの歩幅でも
Chippoke na boku no kono hohaba demo
I'll be able to travel beyond those clouds.
あの雲の向こうまで行けるかな
Ano kumo no mukou made yukeru kana
I put on a bold front.
強がって
Tsuyogatte
End up hurting myself.
キズついた
Kizutsuita
I feel empty inside.
心透かしたように
Kokoro sukashita youni
It's started to rain,
降り出した
Furidashita
And the raindrops
雨粒たちが
Amatsubu tachi ga
Began to repeat their scattered reflections.
乱反射繰り返す
Ranhansha kurikaesu
These straight rays of light
真っ直ぐな光が
Massugu na hikari ga
Start to cross one another.
交差して
Kousa shite
And without telling anyone where they're headed,
行き先も告げぬまま
Yakusaki mo tsugenumama
Across the endless distances,
どこまでも
Doko made mo
They pass through all matter.
突き抜ける
Tsukinukeru
I burn these faint afterimages onto my eyes.
淡い残像　両目に焼きつけて
Awai zanzou ryoume ni yakitsukete
Under this sky,
この空の下
Kono sora no shita
Wherever I am,
どんなとこにいても
Donna toko ni itemo
I should be able to reach
届くはずなんだ
Todoku hazu nanda
The unseen world.
まだ見ぬ世界へ
Mada minu sekai e
Scar appears in Central once again.
再び　セントラルに現れたスカー
エドとアルは人造人間をおびき出すため
In order to lure out the Homunculi, Ed and Al work with Ling in order to purposely attract Scar's attention.
リンと協力して　わざとスカーの注意を引き付ける
The plan works, and Gluttony and Wrath make their appearances.
作戦が功を奏し
現れた人造人間グラトニーとラース
However...
だが
Ran Fan!!!
ランファン
ほう　くないで斬撃をそらしたか
You deflected the slash with your kunai, eh?
Can I eat her?
食べていい
Make it quick.
手早くな
ランファン　しっかりしろ
Ran Fan! Pull yourself together!
You think you can escape my eye?
この私の目から逃げられると思っているのかね
ほう　戦い慣れているな
Seems you're quite experienced.
He's constantly trying to bring his attack toward my left side, my blind side.
常に私の死角　左目側に回り込むか
Gluttony!
グラトニー
Roger!
はぁい
Now, no one can see us here.
さて　ここなら誰も見ていない
I've got a lot to ask you.
いろいろと聞かせてもらおうか
Just what are you folks?
君たちは何者だ
How can you tell what's inside Gluttony?
なぜグラトニーの中が分かる
You're still trying to escape in this situation?
この期に及んでまだ逃げる算段か
その荷物になっているものを捨てれば
If you throw that extra baggage away,
I bet you'll be able to save your own tail.
君一人だけでも逃げきれるだろうに
Baggage, you say?
荷物だと
You're the highest ranking man in this country, right?
あなたは　この国でいちばん偉い人だな
If I remember correctly, your name is Führer President King Bradley.
確か　キング·ブラッドレイ大総統
The king exists for his people.
王は民のためにあるもの　民なくして王はありえない
Without his people, there is no king.
キング·ブラッドレイ
King Bradley, you'll never be able to become a true king!
あなたは真の王にはなれない
You're far too inexperienced.
青臭い
There is no such thing as a true king!
真の王などこの世のどこにもおらん
目に頼りすぎだ
You rely on your eye too much!
From the draft, the exit should be...
風の流れから　出口は
What's wrong?
どうした
I still have this eye, you know!
こちらの目はまだ生きているぞ
Winry.
ウィンリィ すぐ帰って来る
We'll be back soon.
So be good now, you hear?
だからいい子にして　留守番してるんだよ
Winry.
ウィンリィちゃん
We're here.
着いたわよ
Maybe I was thinking of Mr. Hughes as my dad...
私　ヒューズさんにお父さんの背中重ねていたのかな
Come see him every now and then, okay?
たまに　会いに来てあげてね
He always hated being alone.
あの人　結構寂しがり屋だから
Miss Gracia...
グレイシアさん
I heard the Elric Brothers are fighting!
エルリック兄弟が暴れてるってよ
What? Again?!
えっ　また
Military police are running all over the place!
憲兵があっちこっちで走り回ってるぞ
またケンカ　ったく
What are they fighting over this  time?
Geez...
Apparently, they're fighting against that guy who only goes after State Alchemists.
相手は国家錬金術師ばかり狙う例のヤツらしい
They still haven't caught him yet?
まだ捕まってなかったのか
What the heck is the army doing?
軍も何やってんだか
No... What am I thinking?
やだ　なんで重なるのよ
あっ　行き止まり
A dead end!
Dammit!
こなくそ
Nice, my little brother!
ナイスだ 弟よ
Shut up and run!
いいから　早く逃げる
Have we been given permission to engage yet?!
発砲許可は
Not yet, sir!
まだです
Dammit! What's going on?!
くそ　なんでだ
We haven't gotten the signal from Lin yet.
リンからの信号弾は上がってない
兄さんも疲れてきている
Brother is starting to get tired, too.
I should buy some time.
ここは時間を稼ぐか
Scar! You use alchemy, too.
スカー　自分も錬金術を使ってるくせに
Why are you so against alchemists
with the mindset they oppose God?!
なぜ錬金術師を神に逆らう者として毛嫌いする
I told you in East City.
イーストシティでも言ったはずだ
There are ones like you, who create, and ones like me, who destroy.
「貴様ら創る者がいれば壊す者もいる」と
You...
そんなの
You just want to justify murder by using God's name!
そんなの　神の名を持ち出して
殺しを正当化したいだけだろ
Didn't you kill Shou Tucker and Nina by acting as God's hand?!
ショウ·タッカーもニーナも
神の代行者をかたって殺したんじゃないのか
I see. So you guys saw that chimera, too.
そうか　貴様らもあの合成獣を見たのだな
Techniques that give birth to such tragedy...
あのような悲劇を生み出す技術
それが貴様らの崇拝する錬金術か
Is that the alchemy you fools so worship?!
You turned your brother into that form...
お前のその手が
...with your own hands.
弟を救いのない体にしたんだ
Techniques that bring about the creation of matter...
何かを生み出す技術
Isn't that the vanity which gave birth to that chimera?!
そのうぬぼれこそが
あの合成獣を生み出したのではないのか
Even so...
だからって　なんで殺す必要があった
Why did you have to kill her?!
Why did you take her life?!
なんであの子の命を奪った
I'm sure you fools understood it, too.
貴様らも分かっていたのではないか
That chimera would never have been able to return to her original state.
あの合成獣が元に戻れないことを
If I had let her be, she would have received
the same treatment as other experimental animals,
あのままほうっておけば
実験動物と同じ扱いを受け
and she would never have been treated as a human again.
一生人間として扱われなくなるであろうことを
That's right. Back then, we knew in our hearts
there was a possibility Nina would be experimented upon.
そうだ　あのとき僕たちは
ニーナが実験室送りになるかもと
心のどこかでうすうす感じていた
We were just postponing a problem we didn't know how to solve.
どうにもできない問題を先送りにした
何もしなかった
We didn't do anything...
Nothing...
何も
As you say, we, alchemists, have done wrong.
確かに　オレたち錬金術師は間違いを犯してきた
But still, we can't approve of what you're doing either!
だからといって
あんたのやってることを認めるわけにはいかねぇ
Do you recognize...
アメストリス人　ロックベルという医者に覚えはないか
...the name of an Amestrian doctor, Rockbell?
They went to Ishbal during the civil war and continued to treat Ishbalans even after orders were given to destroy the country.
内乱のイシュヴァールに赴いて
殲滅戦の命令が出た後も
イシュヴァール人を助け続けた
Wait, Brother!
待って兄さん
てめぇを助けて　てめぇが殺した医者夫婦に
Do you remember the couple who saved you,
which you killed shortly after?!
覚えはねぇか
Brother!
兄さん
What do you mean?
なんの話
Winry...
ウィンリィ
This man...
この人が　父さんと…母さんを…殺した
...killed Dad... and Mom?
No way...
うそ　殺されたって　助けた人に
They were killed... by one of their patients?
Why?
どうして
What did Dad and Mom do?
父さんと母さんが何をしたっていうの
They didn't do anything to deserve to die... did they?
殺されなきゃならないようなこと
何もしてないでしょう
Give them back...
返してよ
Give back Dad and Mom!!!
父さんと母さんを返してよ
待て　ウィンリィ
Wait, Winry.
Don't...
やめろ　それはダメだ
You can't do that!
Winry!
ウィンリィ
Please, stop!
やめてくれ
恨みたい気持ちは分かる
I understand your resentment.
But all revenge does is give birth to more revenge.
だが復讐は　新たな復讐の芽を育てるだけだ
You must persevere.
耐えねばならんのだ
You're those doctors' daughter, huh?
あの医者の娘か
You have every right to shoot me.
お前には　オレを撃つ権利がある
兄者
Brother!
Brother! The army is already nearby!
兄者すぐ近くまで国軍が来てるんだぞ
そんな研究ほっておいて
Forget about your research and-
待て　もう少しなんだ
Hang on. I'm almost done.
What is that tattoo?
なんだその入れ墨は
ああこれか
Oh, this?
錬金術の基本は理解分解再構築だ
The basics of alchemy are understanding, decomposing, and reconstructing.
My right arm is for decomposing,
and my left arm is for reconstructing.
この右腕が分解　左腕が再構築
東の錬丹術を研究し　私なりにアレンジした
I researched Eastern Alchemy and arranged it myself.
そのうえで分かったことなんだが
What I realized from that...
...is that this country's alchemy is a bit strange.
どうもこの国の錬金術はおかしい
Who cares?!
そんなことはどうでもいい
More importantly, the army's-
それより国軍が
おい
Hey.
Why are you stopping me?!
なぜ止める
We need to get out of here immediately!
一刻も早くここを
頼むから抑えてくれよ
Please, restrain yourself.
お前の兄の研究がイシュヴァールを救うかもしれんのだ
Your brother's research may save Ishbal.
What?
何
Did you hear about the State Alchemists?
聞いたか
国家錬金術師のことを
兵器として
They're using their horrifying powers as
weapons of war and are laying waste to Ishbal.
恐ろしい力でイシュヴァールを蹂躙しているという話だ
Even though we're citizens of Amestris, too...
同じアメストリスの国民であるのに
それは知っているが
I know that, but...
What does that have anything to do with my brother?
それと兄となんの関係がある
お前の兄が
Your brother may discover a way to gain power enough to face those State Alchemists...
国家錬金術師に対抗しえて
更にそれを超える強大な力で
軍を壊滅させる方法を見つけ出すかもしれないのだ
...and perhaps even enough to destroy their army!
力を超える力で
With power that far surpasses theirs...
錬金術で　ヤツらに報復を
To retaliate against them with alchemy!
Make them pay for their sins with blood!
血の報いを
見ろ兄者
Look, Brother.
This is the alchemy that you've been devoting yourself to.
これが兄者の傾倒する錬金術だ
Even if you wish for your efforts to benefit the people and for happiness...
人のため　幸福のためと願っても
No one views it the same way!
誰もそうは見てくれぬではないか
So this is alchemy...
これが錬金術か
こんなものが　イシュヴァールを救うというのか
You think something like this will save Ishbal?
破壊と殺戮を繰り返すだけの　こんなものが
Something like this, which creates an endless cycle of destruction and slaughter?!
Oh no!
いかん
Father! Mother!
父上　母上
無事でしたか
You were safe!
Yes, we're fine.
ああ　大事ない
皆　逃げる準備をしていたのが幸いだった
It's a good thing we were out getting ready to escape.
I made it in time!
間に合った
大事なものをまとめていて遅れた
I was compiling all my critical papers, so I was a bit late.
Critical papers?
大事なもの
You hold on to this.
これ　お前が持っててくれ
What is this?
なんだこれは
My research.
私の研究書だこれしか持ち出せなかった
This was all I could bring.
持って逃げてくれ
Take it and run.
Hang on-
ちょっと待て
If something were to happen to me,
all my research would go to waste.
私にもしものことがあったら
せっかくの研究がパアになる
Why don't you hold on to it yourself and run?!
自分で持って逃げればいいだろう
You're a powerful monk and have gone through rigorous training.
お前は厳しい修行を積んだ　立派な武僧だ
私より　お前の方が生き残る確率が高い
You have a better chance of surviving than I do.
見ろ　足の震えが止まらない
Look.
My legs won't stop trembling.
情けない兄だ
I'm a pathetic older brother.
兄者
Brother...
A soldier?!
国軍兵か
Transmutation circles?!
錬成陣　国家錬金術師
A State Alchemist!
伏せろ
Get down!
Hang in there...
しっかりしろ　死ぬな
Don't die!
D-Dammit... It won't stop bleeding...
くそっ　血が止まらん
His arm...
腕は　弟の腕は　どこだ
Where is his arm...
Dad...
父さん　母さん
Mom...
Everyone... Someone...
みんな　誰か
Live...
生きろ　死んではいけない
You can't die.
イシュヴァールの誇りを見せてやる
I'll show them the honor of an Ishbalan!
だったらなおのこと逃げなさい
If you really feel that way, then run!
そうだ　君を死なせるために治療したんじゃないぞ
That's right! I didn't treat you to let you die!
先生こそ　奥さんと一緒に
You, too, Doctor! You have to flee with your wife...
患者が余計な心配をするな
You're a patient! Don't be worrying about us!
兄者
Brother...
Get down!
伏せろ
No way...
バカな　オレをかばったのか
He... shielded me?
Brother...
兄者
自力で逃げられる人は逃げなさい
If you have the strength to escape, do so!
He woke up!
気づいた
動かないで　傷が開くわ
Don't move! Your wounds will re-open!
あなた　来て　あなた
Dear, come!
Dear!
まだ安静にしてなきゃダメだ
You have to rest!
誰か　そこの台車を
Someone! Get that cart!
彼も一緒に連れていってくれ
Please, take him with you!
Brother, is that you?
兄者か
あぁ　よかった
Thank goodness... Brother was safe-
兄者は助かった…
What the hell is this?!
なんだこれは
Sedatives!
鎮静剤
We're out! We used them up on that other boy!
もうないわさっきの男の子で全部
State Alchemists...
国家錬金術師アメストリス人
Amestrians...
I won't forgive them...
許さん
貴様ら　貴様らに
You... You guys...
ロックベル先生
Dr. Rockbell!
撃つがいい
Shoot me.
Don't shoot, Winry!
撃つな　ウィンリィ
銃を下ろせ
Put the gun down!
そんなもの持っちゃダメだ　ウィンリィ
You shouldn't hold something like that!
Winry!
Shoot me.
撃つがいい
But if you do, I'll take you for an enemy that very instant.
だが　撃てばその瞬間に
オレはお前を敵とみなす
Scar!!!
スカー
てめぇ　ウィンリィに手ぇ出してみろ
If you lay a finger on Winry, I'll-
Kill me?
殺すか　それもいいだろう
That's fine, too.
どちらかが滅ぶまで　憎しみの連鎖は 止められん
The chain of hatred will not end unless one of us dies.
だが忘れるな
But don't forget this!
The ones who first pulled the trigger in that civil war were you...
あの内乱で先に引き金を引いたのは　アメストリス人
貴様らであることを
...the Amestrians!
ダメだ　撃つなよ
No! Don't shoot!
Put the gun down and leave this place!
早く銃を下ろしてここから離れるんだ
ウィンリィ
Winry!
If you can't shoot, then get out of here.
撃てないなら　この場から立ち去れ
You're in the way!
邪魔だ
撃つなぁ
Don't shoot!
Get down!
伏せろ
Brother...
兄者
バカ兄　何やってんだ
You stupid brother! What are you doing?!
Are you trying to get both of you killed?!
二人いっぺんに死ぬ気か
Hurry and get Winry to a safe place!
早くウィンリィを安全な所へ
Winry, let go of the gun.
ウィンリィ　銃を放せ
I couldn't shoot...
撃てなかった
Please don't shoot. I'm begging you.
撃たないでくれ　頼むから
But... he killed Dad and Mom!
だって　父さんと母さんを殺したんだよ
エドとアルも殺そうとして
He tried to kill you and Al, too...
なのに　どうして
But why?!
お前は　ラッシュバレーで赤ん坊を取り上げて
You helped a woman give birth in
Rush Valley, and saved her and her baby.
親子を救った
オレに　立ち上がるための手と足をくれた
You gave me an arm and leg so I could stand again.
お前の手は　人を殺す手じゃない
Your hands aren't meant for killing people.
人を生かす手だ
They're for helping them live.
だから
So...
Let it all out, Let it all out
I don't have to act tough, right?
強がらなくていいんだね
Tsuyogaranakute iindane
The scribbling someone made...
誰かが描いてった
Dareka ga kaitetta
On the wall, of a flower is swaying.
壁の落書きの花が　揺れる
Kabe no rakugaki no hana ga yureru
No one knows their true selves.
自分らしさなんて, 誰もわからないよ
Jibunrashisa nante dermo wakaranaiyo
Even though we both lose and gain
長い長い道の途中で
Nagai nagai michi no tochuu de
By embarking on this long, long path,
失くしたり, 拾ったり,
Nakushitari hirottari
And though there may be days loneliness strikes and makes us weep...
急に寂しくなって, 泣いちゃう日もあるけど
Kyuu ni samishikunatte naichau hi mo arukedo
Let's transform our tears and pains to stars.
涙も　痛みも　星に変えよう
Namida mo itami mo hoshi ni kaeyou
Let's light a candle to illuminate our tomorrow.
明日を照らす　灯りをともそう
Ashita wo terasu akari wo tomosou
And we'll hold our small hands over the fire to create stardust,
小さな手かざして　ふたりで作ろう
Chiisana te kazashite futari de tsukurou
And an eternity that shines so brilliantly.
星屑を　強く光る永遠を探そう
Hoshikuzu wo tsuyoku hikaru eien wo
Farewells may be unavoidable,
さよなら　いつかは来るかもしれない
Sayonara itsuka wa kurukamoshirenai
Yet the seasons continue to change obliviously.
季節はそれでも巡り巡ってく
Kisetsu wa soredemo meguri megutteku
Even if I lose myself, I'll continue to walk...
小さく迷っても　歩いてく
Chiisaku mayottemo aruiteku
Walk by your side.
君と歩いてく
Kimi to aruiteku
That's the only thing I'd like to never change.
それだけは変わらないでいようね
Sore dake wa kawaranaideiyoune
守るためには　何かを捨てねばならぬのか
日本語字幕仕上げ：FAYFAY
Must one throw something away to protect someone?
捨てる覚悟がない者は　失い　地に伏せるのか
And those not prepared to do so will lose both and fall?
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
否 守る覚悟は伝播し
No.
The resolve to protect will spread to all and outshine the disaster.
災厄を凌駕する
次回　鋼の錬金術師
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
FULLMETAL ALCHEMIST
第二十三話　戦場の少女
Episode 23, Girl on the Battlefield.
悲しみの涙は見せない
I won't show tears of sadness...
それが約束
...because I promised not to.